麦克休先生  麦克休太太
Mr. McHugh, Mrs. McHugh,
多亏了二位的支持
your support has helped us
才让这间博物馆达到世界级水平
make this a world-class institution.
新一季  我们将有更精彩的计划案
We have such amazing plans for the new season.
我请海耶斯先生跟你们说说
I'll have Mr. Hayes tell you all about
还有哪些有待赞助的令人激动的展品
the exciting exhibits still available for sponsorship.
他人呢
Where is he?
不知道
I don't know.
快去找他
Go get him.
我相信海耶斯先生马上就会到的
I'm sure Mr. Hayes will be here any second.
默娜快急疯了  欧文
Myrna is freaking out, Owen.
海耶斯先生在哪
Where is Mr. Hayes?
他不在画廊西区
He's not in the west gallery.
我去男厕找找
I'm about to look in the men's room.
接着找吧
Just keep looking for him.
很抱歉
Uh, excuse me...
亲爱的
Darling.
等一下
One second.
我正要把一个家伙丢下布鲁克林大桥
I'm just about to toss a guy off the Brooklyn Bridge.
我相信那个...
Oh, I am sure that...
"卡特·达蒙"会享受短暂的缓刑的
"Carter Damon" would appreciate a short reprieve.
太迟了  他已经壮烈落水了
Too late. He just went kersplat.
有什么需要我帮忙的吗
Now how can I help you?
我邀请了我的表演班周五晚上来这
I have invited my acting class to come here Friday night
排演《傀儡之家》里娜拉那场戏
to do the Nora scenes from "A Doll's House."
多谢提醒
Thank you for the warning.
届时我会闪人
I will make myself scarce.
不不不  亲爱的  这个班将会
No, no, no. No, no, darling, this class could really benefit
从你作家的观点中获益良多
from your perspective as a--as a writer.
你一定得留在这
No, you--you definitely should be here.
妈妈  你打什么鬼主意呢
Mother, what's going on?
这班里有个可爱的姑娘
There's a lovely girl in the class...
-妈妈  -我只是想  也许...
- Oh, mother... - And I just thought maybe--
你不是又想给我介绍对象了吧
You're not trying to fix me up again.
难道你还没从上次的惨败中吸取教训吗
Haven't you learned your lesson after the last fiasco?
惨败  你跟她结婚了呀
Fiasco? You married her.
是的  但婚姻的结果如何呢
Yes, and how did that marriage end?
宝贝  我只是想帮帮你
Honey, I am just trying to help you.
你必须承认你的社交生活
You have to admit that your social life has been
最近可有点匮乏
a bit anemic as of late.
现在我想从布鲁克林大桥上跳下去了
Now I want to throw myself off the Brooklyn Bridge.
亲爱的
Oh, darling.
近几个月以来  你不是写作
All you have been doing for the last few months
就是和贝克特一起办案
is writing and working with Beckett.
现在必须找找对象了
Now I think a fix up is in order.
除非...
Unless...
除非什么
Unless?
你已经有不去找对象的理由了
You have some reason for not putting yourself out there.
在为你的特写镜头做准备吗  卡塞尔
Getting ready for your close-up, Castle?
不  我只是想领悟它所表达的内在含义
No, just trying to discern the hidden meaning.
是针对科技兴起
Is it about the rise of technology,
还是肆虐的自恋
rampant narcissism,
又或者只是因为他家电视太多了
or did someone just have a lot of extra TVs?
有些时候  并不非要明白它的含义
Well, sometimes you don't need to know what it's about.
有些时候  它就只是... 艺术
Sometimes it's just... art.
贝克特探长
Why, Detective Beckett,
你可真是个存在主义者
how very existential of you.
让我猜猜  你在大学修了艺术理论课
Let me guess. Art theory in college.
没  我与艺术课程最近的距离
No. The closest I ever came to taking an art class
只是在一堂课上做过模特
was posing for one as a model.
等等
Wait.
是什么造型
Posing in?
赤裸酮体
Not a stitch.
来见见布莱恩·海耶斯  三十九岁
Meet Bryan Hayes, 39.
博物馆的常务董事
Executive Director of the museum.
看来有人同时赐予了他自由及死亡
Looks like somebody gave him liberty and gave him death.
知道案发时间了吗
Any idea when this happened?
十点时候  最后见到海耶斯的人是默娜·拉姆塞
Hayes was last seen at 10:00 by a Myrna Ramsey,
博物馆的业务发展主管
the museum's Development Director.
10点21分左右发现他的尸体
His body was discovered around 10:21.
所以凶手一定是在这段时间内作的案
So the killer must have struck sometime within that window.
在晚宴期间杀人  胆子还真大
Killing him during the gala, that's pretty ballsy.
依我看  他是碰巧撞见了
My money's on he walked in on the other crime
另一起罪案
being committed here tonight.
它叫做"资本主义之拳"
It's called the "Fist of Capitalism."
一个针对消费者驱动型文化的震撼控诉
A searing indictment of our consumer-driven culture.
有人偷了"资本主义之拳"
Somebody stole the Fist of Capitalism?
有人去查过"社会主义之尻"吗
Anyone check up the Ass of Socialism?
那东西值多少钱  拉姆塞女士
How much was it worth, Mrs. Ramsey?
五千万美元
$50 million.
光是上面的镶钻就价值三千万
The diamonds alone were worth 30.
"资本主义之拳"只是暂借给我们展出的
The fist was on loan to us.
海耶斯先生向所有者保证过展品将被妥善保管
Mr. Hayes assured the owners it would be safe.
我注意到  你们有装摄像头
Y-you know, I notice that you have cameras,
这么说这里一定有保安系统
so there's obviously a security system.
为什么警报没响
Why wasn't the alarm triggered?
按理说有人踏进这间屋子它就该响起的
It should've been, the moment anyone stepped into this room.
我的安全小队正在检查没响的原因
My security team is trying to determine why it wasn't.
好吧  我们需要一份参加晚宴的
Okay, well, we'll need a list of all the people
宾客名单
who attended the gala
以及摄像头的录像
along with the videos from the cameras.
当然
Of course.
我们还得跟发现尸体的人问话
We'll also need to talk to whoever found the body.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
这是我一生中最糟的一天
This is the worst day of my life.
你与海耶斯先生很熟吗  艾丽莎
Were you close to Mr. Hayes, Alyssa?
我们一起工作
We worked together.
我帮助他筹备展览
I helped him curate this exhibit.
他是个很可爱的人
He was a lovely man
并且热心支持像我这样年轻艺术家
and very supportive of young artists like me.
这么说  你是个艺术家啦
Oh, so you're an artist?
我在这里工作
This is my day job.
但我热衷艺术
Art is my passion.
海耶斯先生甚至将我的一件雕刻也展出了
Mr. Hayes even put one of my sculptures in the exhibit.
海耶斯先生有家人吗
Did Mr. Hayes have any family?
好像他的母亲在爱达荷州
A mother in Idaho, I think.
那么海耶斯先生
So Mr. Hayes
今晚本该参加宴会的  对吗
was supposed to work the crowd tonight, right?
你认为他在这里做什么
What do you think he was doing over here?
我知道他有点担心"资本主义之拳"
I know he was worried about the "Fist of Capitalism,"
特别是在晚宴时段
especially with the gala
人山人海  应接不暇的
and the people and all the distractions--
等等  你说他担心今晚可能会
Wait. Are you saying that he was worried
有人把展品偷走吗
someone might steal the fist?
从展品一到他就忧心忡忡
Ever since it got here.
他甚至回顾了这里前两周的
He even reviewed the security video of the fist,
监控录像
going back two weeks,
就是"资本主义之拳"首展的时候
to when we first put it on display.
之前我认为他太过多疑了
I thought he was being paranoid,
但... 我想他大概听到了什么风声
but... I guess he knew something I didn't.
五千万美元
$50 million?
那就是海耶斯不在晚宴上的原因吗
That's why Hayes was awol from the gala.
他来查看"拳头"了
He came to check on the fist.
但那时窃贼已经得手  准备离开了
But the thief was already on his way out with it...
走过这个画廊时
Through this gallery,
窃贼与海耶斯撞了个正着
which put him on a collision course with Hayes.
海耶斯与他正面冲突  他们扭打起来
So Hayes confronts him, they struggle,
然后海耶斯被推倒那些尖刺上
and Hayes get pushed into the spikes.
就在那一刻  毛贼变成了杀人凶手
And at that moment, our thief becomes a killer.
一个通过晚宴进入博物馆的杀人凶手
A killer who gains access to the museum through the gala.
可能性不大
That's not likely.
所有到场的宾客
All arriving guests
都经过了两个安全检查点的检查
were screened at two security checkpoints
然后由认识他们的董事会成员迎接
and then greeted by board members who knew them personally.
比较可能的情况是  窃贼是由屋顶进入的
Odds are the thief came in through the roof--
大概是通风口  然后把警报弄坏
an air vent probably-- and then disabled the alarms.
抱歉  请问你是哪位
I'm sorry. Who are you?
我是萨琳娜·凯耶  博物馆的保险调查员
I'm Serena Kaye, the museum's insurance investigator.
如果窃贼是由通风口入馆
So if the thief got in through the vent,
那他是怎么出去的
then how did he get out?
从卸货区
The loading bay.
保卫把守着每个进口
The guards there checked everyone entering,
但他们没有检查出口
but they didn't check people leaving.
而且卸货区停满了酒筵公司货车
Plus, the bay was full of catering vans.
窃贼可以在那些车子里混入一辆跑路座驾
He could've had one waiting for him and just blended right in.
她挺厉害
Oh, she's good.
理论而已  但证据呢
At theory, but what about proof?
不用证据我也知道自己是对的
I don't need proof to know that I'm right.
这是我的工作
It's my job, and...
而且我还能帮帮你们
I can help you with yours.
怎么说
How so?
找回失窃品我能得到相当它价值百分之一的佣金
I get a 1% finder's fee for recovering stolen objects.
我要那个"拳头"
I want that fist.
你要抓住凶手
You want your murderer.
我们的目的一致
We have common goals.
我可以提供专业意见  帮你破案
I could consult on your case and share my insight.
这个主意很有意思
You know, that is an intriguing idea.
不用  谢谢了  不需要你的帮助
No, thank you. That won't be necessary.
好吧  试试总是没错的
Well, you can't blame a girl for trying.
卡塞尔先生  贝克特探长  失陪
Mr. Castle, Detective Beckett.
我们其实用得上她
You know, we really could've used her.
她挺有料
She has valuable assets.
不是那个意思
Not those kind.
卡塞尔  她只会碍事
Castle, she'd just get in the way.
真的吗
Really?
万一她真的说对了呢
And what if she's on to something?
莱恩  你去查查
Ryan, check and see
是否有可疑的酒筵公司货车
if all of the catering vans are accounted for
并询问所有酒筵公司员工
and interview all the catering staff.
看看有没有人在卸货区看到异常情况
See if anyone saw anything unusual in the loading bay.
这不挺容易的吗
Now was that so hard?
因为某些未知的原因
So for reasons unknown,
海耶斯认为有人会去偷"资本主义之拳"
Hayes thought someone might swipe the "Fist of Capitalism."
我们不知为什么  但他过去查看展品
We don't know why, but he goes to check on it
却因此丢了性命
and ends up paying for it with his life.
是啊  但问题在于
Yeah, except as it turns out,
监控录像并非如此
that's not what the security video shows.
那是怎么样的
What does it show?
展品还完好无损地摆在展馆里
The fist sitting there, undisturbed in the gallery.
盗贼切入了摄像头传输线
The thief tapped into the camera lines
换成循环播放预先录制的影像
and rigged a prerecorded loop.
没有指纹
There's no prints,
但鉴证组发现些痕迹  他们认为是发胶
but C.S.U. did find what they think is hair gel.
发胶吗  在哪里发现的
Hair gel? Where would they find that?
在通风管里
In the air duct.
通风管吗  萨琳娜刚才不是说
In the air duct? That's just what Serena--
碰巧猜对了而已
It's a lucky guess.
卸货区的事也猜对了
So was the call on the loading bay.
什么意思
What do you mean?
两个酒筵公司员工记得有辆蓝色雪佛兰货车停在那
Two of the caterers recall seeing a blue Astro van parked there.
颜色与酒筵公司货车一样  但没有公司商标
Same color as the catering vans, but without the company logo.
真神哪
Imagine that.
有人看到货车里的人长什么样吗
Did we get a description on anyone in the van?
没有  但我全境通缉了那辆车
No, but I put an A.P.B. out on it.
真好  你又犯什么错了
Oh, great. What'd you do now?
闭嘴吧
Shut up.
探长
Detective,
你肯定见过萨琳娜·凯耶了
I believe you've met Serena Kaye.
又见面了
Hello again.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
凯耶小姐向我提出了
Ms. Kaye has presented me with...
一个非常有说服力的建议
a very compelling proposal.
我知道她的建议是什么
Yeah, I am familiar with her proposal.
区别是  我喜欢这个建议
Difference is, I like what I heard.
-盖茨警监  -她懂专业知识
- Captain Gates - She has expertise,
在这件案子上能用得上  可以来做顾问
which she can bring to bear as a consultant on this case.
长官  我更希望与我的组员协作
Sir, I prefer working with my team.
你的小组里就有个毫无特长的顾问
Which includes a consultant with no expertise at anything.
萨琳娜还能提供有价值的帮助
Serena will be a value add for a change.
期待与你的合作
I look forward to working with you.
我不得不说
Well, I will give you this.
你还真是胆大包天
You've got some gigantic balls.
关于窃贼的事  我说对了吗
What I said about the thief, did I turn out to be right?
我看重的是结果  探长
I'm about results, detective.
这是实现双赢的最佳办法
This is the best way for both of us to get what we want.
就当是一次合并
Think of it as a merger.
我看更像是恶意收购
More like a hostile takeover.
莱恩警探会告诉你案情的进展
I'll have Detective Ryan bring you up to speed.
他躲过了这几处的监控摄像头
He bypassed security cameras here, here, and here.
然后我们估计
Then near as we can figure,
他在卸货区坐一辆蓝色货车逃走了
he left via the loading bay in a blue van.
这些...
And, uh, that's...
差不多就是我们掌握的信息
pretty much where we are.
那海耶斯看的那段
What about the security footage
两周前拍摄的监控录像呢
that Hayes was looking at from two weeks ago?
如果凶手曾去踩过点
If the killer had cased out the exhibit,
说不定会被拍到
maybe he's on that video.
但是问题在于
Well-- well, see, that-- that's the problem,
保安把监控录像
because security downloads
下载到U盘中
all the camera footage into flash drives.
海耶斯查看了其中一个
Now Hayes checked out one of the flash drives,
但现在丢失了
but now it's missing.
不在他办公室
It wasn't in his office,
也不在尸体上
and it wasn't on his body, either.
也许凶手知道他被拍到  就拿走了
Maybe the killer took it because he knew he was on it.
我们下一步怎么做
So what's our next move?
重案组发来一份名单
Major case squad sent in a list
上面列出所有可能对"拳头"
of all of the fences that might be interested
有兴趣的黑市买家
in a piece like the fist,
我们正在逐一排查
and so we are looking into that now.
现在牵扯到命案  风头浪尖上很难出手
The fist is too hot to handle now that there's a body on it.
窃贼可能会单独卖掉钻石
So the thief may try to fence off the diamonds,
但肯定不会找你那份名单上的人
but he won't do business with anyone on that list.
被警察盯上的人都被淘汰了
Anyone on it's yesterday's news.
你有什么好主意
Well, do you have a better idea?
同志们
Yo, guys.
有线索  我在检查监控...
Found something. I was going over the security--
埃斯波西托警探  这位是
Detective Esposito, this is
萨琳娜·凯耶
Serena Kaye.
自己人
She's with us.
好吧
Okay.
话说回来
Anyhow,
我们在监控系统的线路上发现了这个
we found these clamped to the wires in the security system.
它的作用差不多就是在警报传到电脑前
It basically cancels out the alarm signals
撤销警报
before they reach the computer.
被称为感信阻  即...
It's called an I.S.I. or--
感应信号阻断器
An inductive signal interrupter.
这个是特制的  我认得它
This one's custom made. I recognize it.
哪里见到的
From where?
在一份关于1992年
From a report I read
布鲁塞尔维梅尔画作失窃的报告
on the 1992 Vermeer theft in Brussels.
那个盗贼还用这个装置偷了许多画
The same thief used these to steal a dozen other paintings.
这是他的作案特征  我知道是谁了
These are his signature. I know who took the fist.
是法鲁克
It's Falco.
然后呢  他没有姓吗
Falco what? Does he have a last name?
没人知道  他从没被抓到过
No one knows. He's never been caught.
甚至没人拍下过他的样子
He's never even been photographed.
他是欧洲顶级的艺术品盗贼
He's a top art thief in Europe,
不过他很多年没犯过案了
though he hasn't worked in years.
传言是  他金盆洗手了
Rumor was, he'd gotten out of the game.
五千万足以引他重出江湖
Well, nothing like $50 million to pull you out of retirement.
现在有了调查方向  我能找到些线索
Now that we have some direction, I can get us some leads.
-很好  我们走  -你不能去
- Great. Let's go. - You can't come.
不好意思  你是不是对"顾问"一词理解有误
I'm sorry. You might have misunderstood the word "consultant."
这是我的案子
This is my case.
那里的人不会对警察开口
The people there won't talk to cops,
但会跟我说
but they'll talk to me.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我也不是警察
Uh, I'm not a cop, either...
那么...
So...
随便你
Fine.
自己人
She's with us?
去联系国际刑警
Let's get ahold of interpol.
尽可能全面地挖掘法鲁克的资料
I want to find out everything we can about Falco.
你是个很有趣的人  卡塞尔先生
You're an interesting man, Mr. Castle.
白天是罪恶终结者  晚上是侦探小说家
Crime fighter by day, mystery writer by night.
你也是很有趣的人
You're pretty interesting yourself.
我们要见一个秘密线人吗
So are we meeting a secret informant?
我猜贝克特不是因为你长得俊才留你在身边
I guess Beckett doesn't just keep you around for your good looks.
这里恶名昭彰  但也便于隐藏身份
This place is as infamous as it is anonymous.
萨琳娜
Serena.
怎么这么久都不联系  你不再爱我了吗
Why you been such a stranger? You don't love me no more?
文  我最近太忙了
Oh, Vin. I've been busy.
忙着干啥  跟这种小白脸一起吗
Busy with what, Jason Bateman over here?
我有次就靠这张脸逃了张超速罚单呢
Hey, that got me out of a speeding ticket once.
文  这次时间不多
Hey, Vin. This is time sensitive.
我们改天再闲谈
We can play catch-up later.
眼下  我想知道有没有人出手顶级钻石
Right now I need to know if anyone's moving D flawless diamonds,
数量不少
a lot of them.
什么时间
Time frame?
最早应该是昨晚
They might have hit the market as early as last night.
那些钻石怎么样
These babies hot?
就像超新星一样闪亮
Like a supernova.
无能为力
Can't help you.
其实
Well...
几天前
You know, there was-- there was a guy
有一个家伙来找过我
who came my way a few days ago,
很谨慎的样子
was real cagey-like.
试探我对一件艺术品是否有兴趣
Tried to take my temp on a piece of art
据说是镶满了顶级钻石
covered with a crapload of Flawless D's.
就是大理石手一类的东西
Yeah, some sort of marble hand or something.
这个人长什么样子
This guy, what did he look like?
萨琳娜说的没错  法鲁克是个狠角色
Serena was right. Falco's a badass.
看这厚厚一叠国际刑警组织的案卷
Look how fat his Interpol file is.
他96年在普希金博物馆偷了件雷诺的作品
He lifted a Renoir from the Pushkin in '96
99年是莫奈的作品
and a Monet in '99,
一直用感应信号阻断器
always using an I.S.I.
看上去法鲁克以前没杀过人
Doesn't look like Falco's killed anybody before.
凡事都有第一次
First time for everything, I guess.
尤其海耶斯挡在了五千万美元的财路上
Yeah, especially when Hayes stood between him and $50 million.
不过据国际刑警称
Though according to interpol,
法鲁克并不为自己干活
Falco doesn't steal for himself.
更倾向于替人卖命
He's more of a gun for hire.
有人想要毕加索的作品  他就为他们搞到手
Someone wants a Picasso, he boosts it for 'em.
这就给我们找凶手提供了第二条路
Which gives us a second path to our killer.
如果我们找不到法鲁克
If we can't find Falco,
那就先找雇他偷东西的人
then we look for whoever hired him to steal the fist.
我知道谁雇的他
I'll tell you who hired him.
安东·麦克休  我的混蛋丈夫
Anton McHugh, my son-of-a-bitch husband.
"拳头"是我和安东共同拥有的
The fist belongs to me and Anton.
我们把它借给博物馆以供展出
We loaned it to the museum from our collection.
你丈夫为什么要偷它
Why would your husband steal it?
为了打击我
To screw me over.
好吧  可你说那东西是他的
Right, but you said that he owns it.
一半是他的
He owns half of it.
你们在申请离婚
You were going through a divorce.
我们只是摆门面罢了
Oh, we keep up appearances,
主要是因为没人愿意放弃
mostly because neither of us will give up
第五大道那间公寓
the Fifth Avenue apartment.
但是这个
But this?
这次安东更下一层楼
This time, Anton has hit a new low.
就是说你们在争夺"拳头"
So then you're fighting over the fist.
我认为它应该留在博物馆里
I think it should stay in the museum.
这是件艺术品
It's a work of art.
应该让大家来欣赏
It should be enjoyed by the public.
是的  但你丈夫不买账
Right, but your husband's not on board.
说"不买账"未免有些轻描淡写
There's an understatement.
上次我们和离婚律师见面时
At our last meeting with the divorce attorneys,
他叫嚣着要不择手段
he screamed at me that he would
把"拳头"抢回去
get the fist back by any means necessary.
但他这么说
Yeah, but saying that he wanted the fist back
并不代表他会雇人去偷吧
doesn't necessarily mean that he hired someone to steal it.
能
Yes, it does,
因为他之前试图偷过
because he's tried to steal it before.
麦克休先生  两周前"资本主义之拳"
Mr. McHugh, a curious incident happened two weeks ago
在去博物馆途中发生了有趣的事件
when the "Fist of Capitalism" was on its way to the museum.
两个自称来自搬家公司的人
Two men claiming to be from the moving company
试图抢走它
tried to intercept it.
据我所知  那是场误会
My understanding is, that was a bit of a mixup.
尽管没有提出指控
Now there were no charges filed,
但两人都有丰厚的案底
but both men had long criminal histories.
我和这事没关系
I had nothing to do with this.
从来没和他们联系过
Never even so much as made contact with them.
有趣的是  你的离婚律师联系过他们
But interestingly, your divorce lawyer did.
就在这场误会前给他们打了数通电话
Made lots of phone calls to the men right before this mixup.
法鲁克在哪
Where's Falco?
谁
Who?
你第一次试图偷窃"拳头"失败后
After your first failed attempt to steal the fist,
你决定雇个专业点的小偷
You decided to hire a better class of thief.
不幸的是  他杀了布莱恩·海耶斯
Unfortunately, he ended up killing Bryan Hayes in the process.
你就成了谋杀从犯
Which makes you an accessory to murder.
你说什么
What?
你疯了吧
You're out of your mind.
等一下
Wait a second.
肯定是乔伊在作祟
I'll bet Joy is behind this.
相信我  麦克休先生
Trust me, Mr. McHugh,
如果你不告诉我们法鲁克的下落
your divorce is gonna be the least of your problems
你该担心的就不是离婚的事了
if you don't tell us where Falco is.
我从没听说过法鲁克这人
I never heard of any Falco,
而且我也没拿那"拳头"  好吗
And I didn't take the fist, all right?
事实是  我压根不想要那东西
The truth is, I didn't even want the damn thing.
我只是想乔伊这么以为而已
I just wanted Joy to think I wanted it.
这又是为什么
And why is that?
我想如果乔伊认为我在乎它
I thought if I made Joy think it meant something to me,
她会把纳帕的葡萄园给我
She'd give me the vineyard in Napa.
现在这也没了
Now that it's gone...
那个肉毒老巫婆要把我洗劫一空了
That bag of botox is gonna clean me out.
你怎么看
So what do you think?
你相信他说的话吗
You believe him?
不管怎样  我们都没有足够的证据
Well, e-either way, we don't have enough
发传票查麦克休家的财务状况
to subpoena the McHughs' financials to, uh--
法鲁克看起来不像在为麦克休干活
Doesn't look like Falco is working with McHugh.
那会是谁
Well, who was he working with?
博物馆的董事  布莱恩·海耶斯
The museum's director-- Bryan Hayes.
死者吗
Our victim?
几天前一个符合海耶斯长相的男人
A man matching Hayes' description met with
和萨琳娜的线人接触过
Serena's contact a few days ago,
打听有关顶级钻石的事
asking about D Flawless diamonds.
所以海耶斯也有份吗
So Hayes was in on the theft?
一定是他雇的法鲁克去偷"拳头"
He must have hired Falco to steal the fist.
只是法鲁克想独吞了它
Yeah, only Falco decided to keep it.
所以他把海耶斯给杀害了
So he murdered Hayes.
如果海耶斯是同谋
If Hayes was a coconspirator,
那或许能助我们找到法鲁克
that might lead us to Falco.
查一下他的财务状况
Let's take a look at his, um, financials--
-那些惯例  -没错
- The usual.  - Yeah.
我去问下我的其他线人
I'll work some of my other sources,
看看是否能找到有关他的线索
see if we can get a line on him.
又要去探访曼哈顿的穷街陋巷吗
Oh, another jaunt into Manhattan's seedy underbelly?
算我一个
Count me in.
抱歉  这次不用找人帮忙
Mm. Sorry. No need for a guy Friday on this one.
我只是去打电话  没什么意思
I'll just be making phone calls, boring stuff.
我稍后给你电话
But I'll catch you later?
随时恭候
Catch me anytime.
凯特
Kate...
是嘛
Rreally?
保险调查员吗
An insurance investigator?
性感的保险调查员
A sexy insurance investigator.
她为我的下一本书塑造了很好的人物形象
I think she'd make a great character for my next book.
你看起来对她很有好感
Well, you seem rather taken with her.
我觉得她
I find her...
很赞
impressive.
她什么样
What's she like?
她是个不合作又自大  顽固的万事通
She's an uncooperative, cocky, stubborn know-it-all.
但她确实挺厉害  是吗
But she is good at her job?
至少卡塞尔这么认为
Yeah, well, Castle seems to think so.
而这令你困扰
And that bothers you.
这当然困扰我
Yes, of course it bothers me.
为什么
Why?
因为他应该
Because he's supposed to be...
应该怎样
Be what?
是我的搭档
My partner.
他应该和我站一边
I mean, he's supposed to be on my team.
而不是神魂颠倒的
He's not supposed to be all smitten.
神魂颠倒
Smitten?
妈妈  我觉得说感兴趣更好
Mother, I think "intrigued" is a better word.
那你打算怎么做
So what's our next move?
做什么
Move?
理查德  真是的
Oh, Richard, honestly.
贝克特表明了她不想谈恋爱
Beckett has made it plain that she's not available
至少现在不想
for now.
而你遇到了这个女人
And now you've met this woman.
她聪明  有魅力
She's smart, she's incredibly attractive,
你又对她感兴趣
You're intrigued by her.
为什么不约她出来呢
Why not ask her out?
这很复杂
It's complicated.
为什么复杂
Why is it complicated?
你知道为什么
You know why it's complicated.
我只知道你告诉我的部分
Only what you've told me.
凯特
Kate...
你到底在怕什么
What are you really scared of...
是怕他不会等你
That he won't wait for you
还是怕他会一直等你
or that he will?
我以为你和萨琳娜在一起呢
Hey. I figured that you were with Serena.
没  她今早要和老板们开会
No. She had a meeting with her bosses this morning.
那你们今早见过面了
Oh. So you already saw her this morning.
没有  她给我发短信来着
No. She texted me. Oh.
你以为我们...
You thought that we were--
是啊  很明显
Yeah. I mean, you know, it's pretty obvious
她对你有意  所以...
that she really likes you, so...
是吗
It is?
那么你觉得我该...
So then you think i should...
追她吗
pursue it?
这个你随意
You know, I mean, suit yourself.
窃贼逃跑用的货车
That, uh, getaway van the thief used?
被弃在皇后区的一个小巷子里
It was dumped in an alley in Queens.
车上有指纹吗
Any prints?
没有  都擦掉了  非常专业
Nope. Wiped clean. Very professional.
但鉴证组在靠枕上发现了那种发胶
But CSU did find traces of that hair gel on the headrest.
他们在查制造商
They're trying to ID the manufacturer.
贝克特  我这里有海耶斯的消息
Hey, Beckett, I got that stuff on Hayes.
这家伙去年花了大把钞票
Well, during the past year, the guy has shelled out
为他母亲的长期护理买单
some major cash to pay for his mother's long-term care bills.
他在经济上入不敷出
Financially, the man was deep underwater.
他可能觉得只有"拳头"能带他脱离苦海
He probably thought the fist was his only solution.
我们还在他的电脑里发现了一些可疑的邮件
We also found some suspicious e-mails on his laptop.
讨论关于博物馆安全系统的问题
Stuff about the museum's security system.
追踪过去是个匿名用户
Tech traced them to an anonymous account.
法鲁克知道如何销声匿迹
Falco knows how to cover his tracks.
其中一封邮件提到窃案发生前一日碰头的事
One of them mentions a meeting the day before the heist.
也就是说如果我们能查到他们的会面地点
So if we can figure out where they met,
就有可能知道法鲁克的身份了
it might lead us to Falco's identity.
我猜会面时间是在
I'm guessing it took place
中午12点到下午2点之间
some time between 12:00 and 2:00 p.m.
因为海耶斯只有这个时候离开了博物馆
since that's the only time Hayes left the museum.
等一下  我这里有他当天的通话记录
Wait a minute. I got something on his phone records for that day.
上午11点06分  他往阿斯卡纳餐厅
11:06 a.m. He made a one-minute phone call
打过一通一分钟的电话
to Ascana's restaurant.
他在订位
He was making reservations.
我打赌是订两个人的位子
How much you want to bet it was for two--
他和法鲁克
Him and Falco?
我记得海耶斯先生
Sure. I remember Mr. Hayes.
三天前  他们坐在角落的小包间
Three days ago. They sat in a corner booth.
他不是一个人  对吧
So he was here with someone?
没错
Definitely.
他俩当时讨论得热火朝天
The two of them were having a real intense conversation.
你记得这个人的长相吗
Do you remember what this person looked like?
她身材高挑
Uh, she was tall,
金发
blonde,
美丽动人
gorgeous.
等等  和海耶斯一起的是个女人
Wait. Hayes was here with a woman?
是的  她有三十多岁  但依旧风姿不减
That's right. She was in her 30's, but still really hot.
等一下
Wait a minute.
她是不是像...
Did she look like...
这样
this?
对  就是她
Yeah. That's her.
是萨琳娜
It's Serena.
她就是我们找的大盗
She's our thief.
不不  谢谢你
No, no. Thank you.
刚和保险公司核实过
Hey. Just got off with the insurance company.
你们猜萨琳娜在他们那里上班前是做什么的
Guess what Serena did before she worked for them.
幼儿园老师
Kindergarten teacher?
艺术品窃贼
Art thief.
未被确认的艺术品窃贼
Alleged art thief.
随便吧
Whatever.
是01到06年几桩大案的重要嫌犯
Suspected of pulling off some major jobs between '01 and '06--
在普拉多  乌菲茨  休斯顿博物馆
Prado, Uffizi, Houston--
但他们都抓不到她的把柄
But they could never pin anything on her.
那她是怎么和保险挂上钩的
Well, how the hell did she end up working insurance?
大约五年前
About five years ago,
她去公司应聘  说是要洗心革面
she went to the company and said she wanted to make good.
还给他们指出了保安的漏洞
Even told 'em where they were going wrong with their security.
让我猜猜看  她建议大家齐心协力
Let me guess. She suggested that they all work together.
至少她始终如一嘛
Well, at least she's consistent.
而且念旧  看来她是使出老伎俩了
And nostalgic. Looks like she's back to her old tricks again.
只不过她加了一招  谋杀
Only now she's added a new one--murder.
所以她才对窃贼如何进入博物馆了若指掌
That's why she knew how the thief got into the museum.
她就是窃贼本尊
She was the thief.
然后她跑来跟我们合作  误导我们
And then she partnered up with us to steer us
去追查那个虚构的法鲁克
to the mythical Falco.
我被她耍了
She played me.
别担心  卡塞尔
Don't worry, Castle.
你不是唯一一个被耍的
You're not the only one.
她参与其中是吗
She's in on it?
我们还不能完全确定  长官
Uh, we're not exactly sure, sir,
但证据显示
But the evidence suggests--
把她缉拿归案  探长  立刻去
I want her in custody, detective, now.
我们不能直接证明她有罪
Our case is circumstantial.
那就去找确凿证据
Get something concrete.
警局被当众羞辱这种事决不能发生
I will not have this department publicly humiliated.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
她现在在哪
So where is she now?
在酒店
At her hotel.
-她邀请我去喝酒  -是吗
- She invited me for a drink. - Did she?
看来她不急于逃之夭夭啊
Doesn't look like she's in a rush to leave town.
那我们得利用好这个优势
Well, then we press our one advantage.
她还不知道我们盯上她了
She doesn't know we're on to her,
我们要不知不觉查出她的底细
so we make a run at her without her finding out.
要怎么做呢
And how are we gonna do that?
简单
Simple.
卡塞尔约她出来
Castle asks her out on a date.
我吗
I do?
这不是如你所愿了吗
It's what you wanted, isn't it?
你只需让她离开房间
All you have to do is keep her out of her room...
和她在酒店的餐厅进餐
and take her to the restaurant at the hotel.
然后
Then...
共度美好时光就行了
just show her a good time.
谢谢
Thank you.
你拖住她的期间
And while you keep her occupied...
我们进入她的房间
we get into her room.
约会上我要做些什么
So what am I doing on this date?
我是不是要
Am I trying to...
套她的话  让她从实招来什么的
trip her up, get her to break?
不用  就拖住她  讲几个笑话
No, just stall her-- make some jokes,
闲扯呗
you know, small talk.
重点是让她别着急回房间
The important thing is to keep her out of her hotel room
给我们搜寻的时间
so we can search it.
怎么样  卡塞尔
So what do you say, Castle?
你的魅力够拖她一个小时吗
Think you can charm her for an hour?
你是认真的吗
Are you serious?
是的
Absolutely.
我本来打算再等一天
I was gonna give you one more day.
然后你就会主动约我出去了
And then you were gonna ask me out yourself?
是的
Mm-hmm.
我是个懂得争取自己所好的女人
Well, I'm a woman who believes in going after what she wants.
看出来了
I can see that.
而且  我喜欢你  这点我毫无掩饰
Besides, I hardly made it a secret that I was attracted to you,
我也能看出你对我的感觉也是一样的
and I could tell you felt the same way about me.
看来我们都不是遮遮掩掩的人啊
Well, looks like neither one of us are very good at keeping secrets.
我这边没发现
Nothin' so far.
你呢
You find anything?
没
No.
你特别想抓住这小妞儿  对吧
Hmm. You really want to nail this chick, don't you?
这个嘛
Yeah, well,
我们的本职工作就是如此啊  缉拿罪犯
it's what we do, isn't it, catch bad guys?
那倒是  但...
Yeah, but...
这次好像不单纯是这样
seems like it might be about more than that.
继续找  好吗
Just keep lookin', okay?
你为什么要当保险调查员呢
So why choose to be an insurance investigator?
这很明显不是那种小女孩们
It's really not something most little girls
梦想拥有的职业
aspire to be when they grow up.
我是最近才转行的
It's a recent career change.
真的吗
Really?
那你以前是做什么的
What did you do before?
其实我是个贼
Actually, I was a thief.
别逗了
Get out.
是博物馆那边非要这样叫
Well, that's what the museums like to call me.
我更倾向于称之为"艺术寻回人"
I prefer to think of myself as an art retriever.
有什么区别吗
What's the difference?
我所获取的艺术品都是从
Well, the pieces I took had already been stolen
原主人那里掠夺走的
from their rightful owners--
被纳粹  暴君  政府之类强取豪夺
Taken by nazis, despots, governments.
艺术品在博物馆展出
Just because a piece is in a museum
不代表艺术品就属于那里
doesn't mean it belongs there.
你不是开玩笑吧
Seriously?
我专门负责将艺术品归还给真正的主人
I specialized in returning art to their rightful owners,
最早是从一名党卫军手中
starting with a small Rembrandt
夺回他从我爷爷那夺走的伦布兰特画作
an S.S. Officer took from my grandfather.
所以你有点类似
So you were kinda like the, uh,
女性版的印第安纳·琼斯
Female Indiana Jones,
只是你没带牛仔帽和鞭子
only without the hat and whip.
只是没戴帽子而已
Well, without the hat.
好热
It's gettin' hot in here.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
我们别吃甜点了  如何
Why don't we skip dessert?
我们急什么呢
Oh, well... What's the rush?
我听说这里的草莓松饼相当不错
I hear the strawberry shortcake here is excellent.
你难道不想到我房间
Wouldn't you rather come up to my room
喝一杯吗
for a drink?
据说那草莓非常的新鲜
The, uh, strawberries are supposed to be really fresh.
好吧
Well, great.
客房服务就点它们
We can order them from room service...
还有浓浓的鲜奶油
with extra whip cream.
我找到了些东西
I think I found something.
是萨琳娜和一些销赃犯之间的信息
It's a message between Serena and a bunch of fences.
猜猜是谁想脱手一批顶级钻石
Guess who's trying to sell d flawless diamonds.
我也找到了些东西
I think I found something, too--
作案的工具
The tools of the trade...
还有一个感应信号阻断器
As well as an I.S.I.
到了
There it is.
天际套房
The skyline suite.
你们在这儿干什么
What--what are you doing here?
以偷窃和谋杀的罪名
Arresting you for theft...
逮捕你
and murder.
等等  你是说
Wait. So now you're telling me
你认为不是她干的吗
that you don't believe she's in on this?
她为什么要告诉我她是小偷呢
Why would she tell me she's a thief?
为什么要坦白
Why offer that up?
她想先给你点甜头
Because she's feeding you just enough truth
好让你接受她撒下的弥天大谎
so that swallowing the lies is easier.
我觉得不是她干的
I don't think she's behind this.
你根本没用大脑在思考
Yeah, well, you're thinking with the wrong body part.
只是接个吻而已
It was only a kiss.
是你要我这么做的  拖住她
I was doing what you told me to, keeping her occupied.
我是在帮你们拖时间
I was trying to give you enough time
好让你们搜查她的房间
so that you could search her room.
没错  房间  我们从房间里找出了
Yes, the room-- the room where we found
手提箱和那些邮件
the suitcase and the e-mail,
这些都是对她不利的证据
which all stands as evidence against her right now.
我只是觉得我们该听她解释一下
I just think we should give her a chance to explain.
我们吗  不  你休想
We? No, there is no way
跟我一起审讯她
we're going in on the interrogation together.
别这样
Oh, come on.
抱歉了  卡塞尔  可现在
I'm sorry, Castle, but right now,
基于这段对话和你在酒店的举动
based on this conversation and your behavior in that hotel,
你明显是在偏袒她
it is obvious that you have been compromised.
我只是照着
I was only doing...
你说的在做
what you asked.
这次我就不出席了
I thought I'd sit this one out.
我不得不说
I gotta hand it to you.
你设计的这一长线骗局
this whole long con you've got going...
令人惊叹
It's impressive.
向保险公司示好
Cozying up to insurance companies,
告诉他们你想改过自新
telling them that you want to go straight,
同时又在等待下一个目标
all the while waiting for your next score.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
唯一的麻烦是  你知道你需要海耶斯
The only catch was that you knew you needed Hayes
可如果让他活下去
but you knew you couldn't get away with it
你就无法脱身
if you let him live,
于是你潜入我的调查
so you insinuated yourself into my investigation
来掩盖你的痕迹
to cover your tracks.
我本以为里克才是你们组里爱编故事的那个
And here I thought Rick was the only writer on your team.
里克吗  你俩进展到可以互称名字了吗
Rick? You guys on a first-name basis now?
那个
Well...
他在酒店走廊上和她亲热来着
He was making out with her in the hotel hallway.
贝克特叫我拖住她
Beckett told me to stall her.
她叫你用舌头去拖吗
She also tell you to use tongue?
我不需要编故事
I don't need to spin stories.
我知道你在抢劫的前一天
I've got you meeting Bryan Hayes
和布莱恩·海耶斯碰了面
the day before the heist.
没错  为了确认晚宴时的安保情况
Yes, to go over security for the gala.
他很担心
He was concerned.
担心吗
Concerned?
他参与了劫案
He was involved.
当时我并不知道这一切都是他在做戏
I didn't know that it was all an act at the time.
如果那次碰面光明正大
If that meeting was so innocent,
你之前为什么不告诉我们呢
then why didn't you tell us about it before?
被他那样耍得团团转
Because it's not like I'm particularly proud of the fact
也不是什么值得骄傲的事
that I didn't figure out what he was up to.
要是我识破了他  那雕塑不会被偷走
If I had, then the sculpture wouldn't be stolen,
而他或许还活着
and he might still be alive.
天  她的"盗亦有道"
Man, she's really selling the whole
还真是装得有模有样啊
"thief with a heart of gold" act.
也许这不是假装
Maybe it's not an act.
她看起来相当镇定
She is being really calm in there.
没错  不可思议地镇定
Yeah, like strangely calm.
也许真不是她干的
Maybe she didn't do it.
不然她就是个疯子  这样的话
Either that or she's a psychopath, in which case...
你还真会挑人啊
you sure can pick 'em.
我们找到了你用来闯入
We found the tools that you used
博物馆的工具
to break in to the museum--
绳索  挂钩
The rope, grappling hook,
开锁工具
lock picks.
我专门从事物归原主的工作
I specialize in recovery.
保险公司不在乎我是如何
The insurance companies don't care how
找回这些东西的  只要能找回
I get the pieces back, just that I do.
所以从根本上说  你还是个贼
So basically, you're still a thief.
物归原主  不算偷
Recovery, not theft.
在黑市倒卖顶级钻石
And what part of recovery involves trying to sell
算哪门子物归原主啊
D flawless diamonds on the black market?
法鲁克有可能要卖掉钻石
Falco may try to move those stones.
我是想要赶走他的潜在销赃犯
I was trying to flush out his possible fences.
我了解你的底细  探长
Listen, I've done my homework on you, detective.
我知道你是个聪明  有条理性
I know that you're a smart, methodical cop
直觉又准的警察
with great instincts.
你的直觉在告诉你
And those instincts are telling you right now
我是清白的
that I'm innocent.
基于某些原因  你对它们视而不见
For some reason, you're ignoring them.
为什么呢
Why is that?
凯耶女士  你说你的工作是物归原主
Ms. Kaye, your job is recovery, as you call it.
我的工作则是解决凶案
my job is to solve this homicide.
那为何不把你的个人因素放在一边
Then why don't you put aside your personal agenda
先听听我的不在场证词
and ask me for my alibi
这样我们就能继续调查了
so we can move on with this investigation?
我先声明  我接到电话的那天
For the record, I was in a business meeting
我正和我的一位老板在开会
with one of my bosses when I got the call...
你可以去调查
If you want to check.
如果你说的都是事实
If you're telling the truth,
那你为什么总在我们背后搞鬼
Then why have you been going behind our backs?
因为在我看来  警察总是很碍事
Because in my experience, the police just get in the way.
我的工作是找回雕像  而不是好好配合
My job's to recover the sculpture, not play nice.
不过你说得对
But you're right.
我把这案子当做一般案子处理  可这案子不一般
I've been treating this like a regular case, and it's not.
所以我保证  从现在开始  知无不言
So I promise, from here on out, no more secrets.
没那个必要
It won't be necessary.
我们不会再合作了
We won't be working together anymore.
如果我说  我知道法鲁克是谁
Would it change your mind if I told you,
你会改变主意吗
I know who falco is?
你们现在看的是
What you're watching right now
两周前博物馆展览的
is security footage from the museum exhibit
监控录像
from two weeks ago.
你偷了海耶斯的U盘吗  怪不得找不到
You stole Hayes' flash drive? That's why it went missing?
别忘了  你是要让我们相信你
Remember, you're trying to get us to trust you.
至少我亲你的时候是认真的
At least I meant it when I kissed you.
闪存盘留给你也没用
It wouldn't have done you any good.
你不知道该找些什么
You wouldn't know what to look for.
看到那个男人了吗
You see that guy right there?
他正在踩点
He's casing the joint.
你怎么知道
How can you tell?
相信我  我看得出来
Trust me. I can tell.
-你是说那就是  -法鲁克
- So you're saying that's-- - Falco.
你之前为什么不告诉我们
Well, why didn't you tell us this before?
我只是没找到机会拿给你看
Well, I just didn't get a chance to show you.
-我猜你是挺忙的  -好了  好了
- I guess you were busy. - Okay, okay.
我们应该专注于怎样抓到他
Perhaps we can just focus on getting this guy.
这能帮上我们什么忙呢
Well, how's this supposed to help?
我们连他的真名都不知道
We don't even know his real name.
唯一能做的是把照片发给联邦运输安全局
Well, the only thing we can do is send photos out to T.S.A.
发布全境通告
and put out an A.P.B.
否则  再没有更多的信息
Otherwise, without more information,
这录像对我们也没什么帮助
it's not gonna do us any good.
如果我能告诉你他住在哪家酒店呢
What if I could tell you which hotel he was staying at?
在通风口和货车靠枕上找到的发胶
The gel in the vents and on the headrest of the van,
鉴证组已经证实是
C.S.U. identified it as a proprietary formula
为威塞克斯酒店特制的一种专有配方
made exclusively for the Wessex Hotel.
在纽约这酒店只有一家
There's only one in the city.
我们把照片拿去给酒店员工瞧瞧
Let's get the photos out to the hotel employees.
只要有员工认得他  我们就能抓住他了
If one of them recognizes him, we got him.
这就去
Right on.
纽约警察  纽约警察
NYPD! NYPD!
举起手来  快把手举起来
Let me see your hands! Let me see your hands right now!
快把手举起来
Let me see your hands right now!
举起手  快点
Hands, right now!
你好  法鲁克
Hello, Falco.
法鲁克
Falco?
我真不知道你们在说什么
I've got no idea what you're talking about.
我叫霍特  威廉·霍特
My name is Holt. William Holt.
是的  威廉·霍特  持英国护照
Yes, William Holt, British passport.
你两周前刚到纽约
You just got into town two weeks ago.
十年前毕沙罗的画被偷时
You also happened to be in Bilbao
你刚巧也在毕尔巴鄂[西班牙港口]
ten years ago when the Pissarro went missing.
而十五年前埃尔·格列柯的画被偷时
And then in Berlin 15 years ago
你刚巧在柏林
when that El Greco disappeared.
我真不知道那事
Don't know anything about that.
别装了  法鲁克
Drop the act, Falco.
我们拿到了两周前你探查博物馆的录像
We've got a video of you casing the museum two weeks ago.
就是你  不是吗
That is you, isn't it?
每当我来到一个新的城市
Whenever I come to a new town,
我总是会花时间去瞻仰这个城市的珍藏
I always take time out to admire the city's treasures.
那也算犯罪吗
Is that a crime?
不不  当然不是
No, no.
但是偷偷溜回去偷走它们就是了
But sneaking back in and stealing them is.
看着眼熟吗
Look familiar?
它被用于解除
It was used to disarm
博物馆的安保系统
the security systems in the museum.
在毕尔巴鄂和柏林也找到了相同的东西
They also found matching ones in Bilbao and Berlin.
就算你说的是真的
If you say so,
我也从没见过那样的东西
I, for one, have never seen anything like that.
你住的酒店
The hotel that you're staying it,
很漂亮  对吗
it's nice, isn't it?
他们甚至提供独一无二的护发用品
They even have their very own exclusive hair products.
在风道系统里发现了护发品留下的痕迹
Hair products that left a trace in the air duct system.
顺便说下  用发胶
And by the way, uh... hair gel,
没有男子气概唉
not very manly.
在我下榻的酒店有成百上千的住客
Hundreds of people are staying at my hotel,
我很肯定
and I'm pretty sure
你们在那上面没找到指纹
you didn't find prints on that.
所以
So...
你们到底准备控告我什么呢
What exactly were you planning to book me on?
你们追踪的法鲁克
This Falco person you're chasing...
你们确定他就是你们要找的人吗
Are you sure he's your guy?
因为据我所知  他可不是杀人犯
From what I know about him, he's no murderer.
或许他并没有如你们所想  牵扯其中
He may not be as involved as you think.
他在给我们暗示一些讯息
He's trying to tell us something.
是啊  很艺术地告诉我们去死吧
Yeah, to politely go to hell.
不  他违背原则告诉我们
No, he went out of his way to tell us,
他不是凶手
he's not the murderer.
在审讯室  大多数人都说这话
Well, most people do that in the room.
鉴证组在酒店里找到什么证据没
C.S.U. come back with anything from the hotel?
什么都没找到
Nothing.
没发现任何装备  没发现拳头
No equipment, no fist.
你怎么看这事
What are you thinking?
他知道些事
He knows something.
但他不能告诉我们
But he can't tell us
因为说了就证明他在凶案现场
without admitting he was there.
让我跟他谈谈
Let me talk to him.
你在开玩笑  对吧
You're kidding, right?
他是嫌疑犯  而你又不是警察
He's a suspect, and you're not even a cop.
不  我是小偷  跟他一样
No, I'm a thief, like him.
他会愿意跟我谈的
He'll talk to me.
坏警察三振出局
Bad cop struck out,
好警察乘虚而入吗
good cop gets a turn?
我可不是警察
I'm not a cop.
那你是谁
Then who are you?
那要看你问谁了
That depends on who you ask.
我是苏黎世的幽灵
I'm der Geist in Zurich,
西班牙的金钱豹
Pantera in Spain.
法国的警察叫我小淘气
Police nationale know me as Gaston.
至于你
But you...
可能会叫我
probably know me as...
豺狼
Jackal.
普拉多那次
The Prado.
07年
07?
是你干的
Are you saying that was you?
你是如何通过声音传感器的
How'd you get by the Sound Sensors?
我让俄国人为我造了个声波消音器
I had the Russian build me a wave cancellation box.
我听说他也为你波士顿那单做了个
I heard he built one for you for the Boston job?
普拉多那儿可不容易出去
That's no easy exit, Prado.
你是怎么把它带出去的
How did you get the piece out?
警卫忙着欣赏我的身材
The guard was so busy checking out my assets,
以致于他没注意到
that he didn't notice me
我把戈雅画后的绊网给剪了
cut the trip wire on the Goya's back.
夜幕初降时  我回去偷走了
I came in later on a skyline and whipped it right out.
真没想到
I'll be damned.
但你如今在这
But now you're here,
和警察共事
working with the cops.
所以你肯定是被抓了
So you must have got caught.
我变精明了
Mm. I got smart.
某一天你会发现
One day you realize
你或者他人终会受伤
that you or someone else is going to get hurt.
我没杀他
I didn't kill him.
但是你在凶案现场
But you were there.
你觉得她能使他开口吗
Think she'll get him to talk?
谁知道呢  卡塞尔
Who knows, Castle?
也许她会把真相亲出来
Maybe she'll kiss it out of him.
我不是被雇佣去偷"拳头"的
I wasn't hired to steal the fist.
我的联系人告诉我  我是被雇
My contact told me that I was being paid
去检验安保系统的缺陷
to test their security for vulnerabilities.
我潜进去  弄坏警报器
I was to break in, disable the alarm,
悄无声息的走出来
and walk out undetected,
要在晚十点前搞定
all before 10:00 p.m.
因为麻烦我再次出山
And for my trouble,
我收了20万定金
I got 200 grand in advance.
谁雇的你
Who hired you?
亲爱的  谁知道呢
Oh, church and state, love.
一切都是通过第三方交易的
Everything goes through a third party.
你明白的  那样更安全
You know that. It's safer that way.
知道  直到你被下套了
Mm. Yeah, until you get set up.
真正的窃贼需要你去破坏警报器
The real thief needed you to disable the alarms.
对  很明显就是这样
Yeah, apparently.
你看到什么了吗
What'd you see?
最初什么都没看到
Nothing at first.
我的意思是
I mean...
一切都太顺利了
it had all been too easy.
我都快要回到卸货区了  才反应过来
I got halfway back to the loading bay when it hit me--
报警器已经被我解除了
I mean, I'd already disabled the alarms, right?
而"拳头"就在那
And it was just, oh, sitting there.
你为了"拳头"折返了
You went back for the fist.
诱惑十足  五千万啊
It's an awful lot of temptation, $50 mil.
当我回到那里时
When I got back to the room,
有个女人正走向"拳头"
there was a woman walking toward the fist.
我就赶紧跑路了
So I got the bloody hell outta there.
这个女人长什么样
This woman, what did she look like?
我只是瞟了一眼
I barely got a glimpse.
我只确定一点
All I can say for sure is,
她穿着一条黑裙子
she was wearing a black dress.
贝克特
Come on, Beckett.
他没有任何理由说谎
He's got no reason to lie.
他是个小偷
He's a thief.
他有很多理由撒谎
He's got plenty of reasons to lie.
但不是在这事上
Not about this.
他知道你在他身上没查到什么
He knows you've got nothing on him.
他只需坐着等  而你必须释放他
All he had to do was wait, and you'd have to release him.
如果法鲁克说的是实话
If Falco is telling the truth,
考虑到海耶斯入不敷出
then with Hayes' money trouble,
给法鲁克那20万便排除了他的嫌疑
the $200,000 payment to Falco rules him out.
那为什么他会去酒吧  询问如何把钻石脱手
Then why would he go to the bar, asking about fencing diamonds?
因为他多疑有人会偷走"拳头"
Because he was paranoid someone was trying to steal the fist.
不是多疑  他是对的
Not paranoid. Right.
也就是说  凶手很可能就是
Which means our killer's probably
法鲁克看见走进那间房去偷"拳头"的人
whomever Falco saw going into the room with the fist.
当海耶斯妨碍到她时   她就把他杀了
And when Hayes got in the way, she spiked him.
他有没有说那个女人长什么样
Did he say anything about what the woman looked like?
他只说她穿着条黑色的裙子
Just that she was wearing a black dress.
二百多人出席了晚宴
There were over 200 people at that gala,
一半以上的女人都穿着黑裙子
and half of those women were wearing black.
更重要的是
And more importantly,
如果她不是从卸货区离开的
if she didn't leave by the loading dock,
那她到底是怎么把"拳头"从博物馆里弄走的
then how did she get the fist out of the museum?
是呀  到底是怎么弄走的呢
Yeah. How did she?
她等到法鲁克黑了监视器以后
She waits for Falco to finish disabling the system,
就从晚宴走到这里
and then she comes in through the gala.
她知道监视器已经被黑了
And with the alarm system deactivated,
于是便拿起"拳头"
she grabs the fist.
但海耶斯一直对安保系统不放心
But Hayes is paranoid about security,
所以他就进来查看展品
so he comes in to check on the exhibit.
他把她逮了个正着
He catches her...
于是她不得不杀了他
And she's forced to kill him.
现在她要赶在别人发现
Now she's in a hurry to leave
尸体和她手中的"拳头"前离开这里
before someone discovers her with the fist and a body.
但是她不能拿着"拳头"从晚宴走出去
Ah, but she can't take it out through the gala
那样一定会被人看到
without being spotted...
不然的话  卸货区的酒筵公司员工
without one of the catering staff
会注意到黑衣女子
noticing her dressed in black.
晚宴和卸货区是仅有的两个出口
Well, those are the only two exits.
而这两个出口都太危险了
And both of those choices leave too much to chance.
她无论走哪个都很容易被逮到
She would've easily gotten caught.
这么说她不能从晚宴离开
So if she can't take it through the gala
也不能从卸货区离开
and she can't take it through the loading bay,
那她到底是怎么把"拳头"带出去的呢
how the hell did she get it outta here?
也许她根本没拿出去
Maybe she didn't.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我的意思是
What I mean is...
你在干吗
What are you doing?!
它一直就没离开博物馆
it never left the museum.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle.
看来我找到了这件案子的重大突破口
Looks like I broke this case wide open.
你要见我吗  警探
You needed to see me, detective?
没错  我们想跟你谈谈你的现代雕塑
Yes, we need to talk to you about your installation.
天啊  发生什么事了
Oh, my god. What happened?
这是我对这件艺术品的全新诠释
It's a new interpretation I'm working on.
我称它为  人赃并获
I call it...busted.
这件艺术品被毁了  是谁干的
It's ruined. Who the hell did this?
更重要的是  是谁把"拳头"放到里面的
More to the point, who put the fist in it?
"拳头"在这里面吗
The fist was inside it?
这样一来  盗贼就不用担心
That way, the thief didn't have to worry
怎么把它运出去了
about smuggling it out.
她可以返回派对
She could simply rejoin the party.
她
She?
我们知道偷走拳头的人
We know that whoever stole the fist
是个身穿黑裙的女人
was a woman wearing a black dress --
她还杀害了海耶斯先生
The same woman that killed Mr. Hayes.
如果我记得没错的话
If I remember correctly,
你当晚穿了一条黑裙子
you were wearing a black dress that night.
当晚出席的所有女人都穿着黑裙子
So was every woman in here.
没错  可是只有一个人知道
Yes, but only one of them knew
这件艺术品里
that there was a compartment
有个隔层
inside that piece nearby.
这个计划本是完美无缺
It was the perfect plan
直到布莱恩·海耶斯突然出现  看到了你
until Bryan Hayes showed up and saw you.
等一下  这  这不是我干的
Wait. I-it wasn't me.
我发誓
I swear.
你是说  不是你一个人干的
You mean, it wasn't just you.
你没有那么多钱来雇法鲁克
You didn't have the money to pay Falco,
但是你凭借你的职务之便
but you did use your position
把这件艺术品放到展会上来展览
to place the piece in the exhibit.
我什么都没干
I didn't place anything.
我的作品就跟这里的其它作品一样
My piece was selected by the board,
都是被董事会选中的
just like all of the art in here.
没错  而且等到展览结束后
Yes, and when the exhibit was done,
这件展品还会回到你手上
it would come back to you,
只不过那时它的价值就升了五千万美金
only worth about $50 million more.
不  它根本就不会回到我手上
No, it wasn't coming back to me.
它上周就已经被卖掉了  卖给了
I sold it last week. It was going to...
天啊
Oh, my god.
我觉得艾丽莎的作品很吸引我
I found Alyssa's work compelling.
我不明白我为什么要跟你们解释我的艺术鉴赏力
I'm not sure why I'm having to justify my taste in art.
因为这件艺术品里恰恰
Because this particular piece just happened to have
藏着铜拳
a bronze fist in it.
你找到我的"拳头"了
You found my fist.
没错  是你把它放到那的
Yes, right where you put it.
现在你该好好想想
You know, right about now is where you should be thinking
你推倒海耶斯到底是故意的还是个意外
about whether pushing Hayes was an accident or not,
因为一念之差
because that's gonna make
可是相差着三十年的刑罚呢
a 30-year difference in your prison sentence.
你认为是我杀了布莱恩·海耶斯吗
You think I did that to Bryan Hayes?
我们已经拿到了搜查令去查你的财务情况
Now we've obtained a warrant for your financials,
而我们会找到了证据证明你付给
and we will find evidence of the $200,000
威廉·霍特也就是法鲁克
you paid to William Holt,
二十万美金来黑掉博物馆的监控系统
also known as Falco, to disable security at the museum.
抱歉  亲爱的  我不知道你在说什么
I'm sorry, dear. You've lost me.
鉴证组发现"拳头"上布满了你的指纹
C.S.U. found your fingerprints all over the fist.
那是当然  "拳头"本来就是我的东西
Of course they did. It belongs to me.
带血的指纹  他的血
Bloody fingerprints -- his blood,
你的指纹
your prints.
一切都结束了
It's over.
你杀了人  麦克休太太
You killed a man, Mrs. McHugh.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我丈夫要把它从我手里夺走
My husband was going to take it away.
我只是拿走了原本就属于我的东西而已
I just took what was rightfully mine.
布莱恩·海耶斯突然出现
Bryan Hayes showed up out of nowhere.
他看到我手里拿着"拳头"
He saw me with the fist in my hands.
我还能怎么办
What was I supposed to do?
你知道讽刺的是什么吗
You know what's ironic?
你丈夫本来就计划把"拳头"留给你
Your husband would've let you have the fist.
他根本就不想要
He didn't even want it.
检察官说她丈夫打过无数个电话来
The D.A. said that her husband called several times,
恳求检察官允许他指证自己的妻子
begging to testify against her.
我什么时候可以把"拳头"拿回来
When can I collect the fist?
是保险公司在问
The insurance company's asking.
现在它还是物证
Well, it's in evidence.
一旦案子结了  你就可以把它拿回去了
Once the case is resolved, they'll release it.
我想向你道谢
I want to thank you.
要是没有你  我也找不回"拳头"
I couldn't have done this without you.
我真的很感谢你
I'm really grateful.
这么说你会把你的佣金分我点咯
So does that mean you're cutting me in on the finder's fee?
我还没感激到那个地步
I'm not that grateful.
我
Well, I, uh...
我想我们最终都得到了自己想要的东西
think we all ended up with what we wanted.
没错
Yeah.
你知道
Um, you know...
在你跟卡塞尔的那次约会之后
after you and Castle went on that date --
哪里是约会  纯粹是骗局
More like a sting.
他  一直坚信你跟这件事无关
He...never thought that you were involved.
虽然我当时怀疑你  但他一直相信你
He believed in you, even when I didn't.
你为什么要告诉我这些
Why are you telling me this?
我只是  我只是觉得你应该知道
I just -- I, I think that you should know
跟你交往的是个什么样的人
what kind of person you're dealing with.
咖啡来了  美女们
Here we are, ladies.
谢谢
Thank you.
出什么事了吗
Anything wrong?
没有  我该
Uh, no. I should --
我要去把东西归档了
I'm just gonna go and file some stuff.
我  我要回酒店了
Uh, and I'm -- I'm going back to my hotel.
我本想邀你跟我一块回去
I would ask you to come,
但是  如我所说
but...it's like I said,
我不偷属于别人的东西
I don't steal things that belong to someone else.
你们俩没去约会吗
You guys didn't go out?
没
No.
为什么
Why?
因为我去不起
Because I can't afford it.
博物馆刚给我发来一张账单
The museum just slapped me with a bill
让我赔我打烂的那个展品
for that exhibit I broke.
就是说呀  在我帮他们破案之后
I know. You'd think they cut me slack
他们好歹也该放我一马吧
after the whole "helping to solve the murder" thing.
看来纽约警局好歹也得
I guess the least the NYPD could do
请你吃个汉堡了
is take you out for a hamburger.
同意
I accept.
走吧
Let's go.
这钱都够我供阿丽克西斯读大学的了
I could put Alexis through college on this.
是啊  再读医学院都够了
Yeah, and med school.
还好老子有的是钱
Thank god I'm rich.